

ABOUT ME

I'm all about sounds and music. Every job I've had since being a teenager was somehow related to music.

Last four years were a journey of being a freelance "sound guy" for me and now I am really looking forward to joining a team of dedicated professionals in order to obtain new skills, grow as a person and most importantly create awesome experience for end users.

CONTACT

mzimean@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikezimean/ @mikezimean on any messenger/network https://mikezimean.com

MIKE ZIMEAN

Composer / Sound designer / Producer

SKILLS

- Composition
- Audio production
- Mixing/Mastering
- Recording techniques
- Foley recording
- Wwise knowledge

SOME OF THE ACHIEVEMENTS I AM PROUD OF:

- Olivia Lynn songs topping iTunes UK Country charts several times
- Black Feedback Film Festival 2021 award for movie Foley/SFX ("Hallucinated")
- Sound design and music for Jean Paul Gaultier's Scandal perfume ad
- Composing and producing music for two musicals (Room 46, Stupid Wig)
- 100+ five star reviews on Fiverr, and all the feedback being five star only



Hard skills:

My primary DAW is Presonus Studio One. However I also have solid understanding of Steinberg Cubase, FL Studio and lots of other DAWs, editors and software suites and bundles.

Insights of microphone techniques acquired over the years of foley production and instruments/amps/vocal recording.

Intermediate skills in Audiokinetic Wwise.

Intermediate to advanced skills in music theory, composition, arrangement, mixing and mastering music. Advanced guitar playing skills.

Basic understanding of DaVinci Resolve.

Basic experience in Git.

Soft skills:

Friendliness

Proactivity

Organization

Ethics

Empathy

Respect and support

Eager to acquire new knowledge

Not afraid of asking questions

Experience:

2019 - 2022 - Audio production freelance (music, foley, sound design)

2006 - 2021 - Actively performing musician (cover band and a couple of my bands, 1800+ gigs)

2011 - 2015 - Rehearsal studio complex owner

2009 - 2011 - Musical Instruments Store Manager

Education:

2005 - 2008 - Rostov State University - Advertisement, Marketing, Management in Media

2022 - Sound Design Institute - Wwise Course.

Volunteer work:

I took and keep taking part in number of activities related to animal protection, eco and urbanist initiatives, refugee support and independent journalism encouragement.

Personal info:

My main work goals and values include:

- streamlining my workflow in order to make things happen really fast;
- the idea that competence comes from knowledge, experience and skills, not from gear or facilities (although I'm actually a bit of a gear enthusiast and collector too :)
- a firm belief that the concept of "talent" is an overrated abstract matter, that devalues all the hard work behind the aforementioned competence.

That's why I never get bored with learning new stuff and obtaining new relevant skills.